[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ MUSIC INTENSIFIES ]
[ TOWNSPEOPLE SPEAKING IN ITALIAN ]
[ AMORTH IN ITALIAN ] That 's a beautiful pig .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Only the best , Father .
[ IN ITALIAN ] This way , Father .
[ IN ITALIAN ] The boy is showing
all the classical signs of possession , Father Amorth .
Has the family consulted a doctor ?
Many , many doctors .
What are the signs of possession ?
He converses in English , Father .
- [ BOY YELLS ] - [ THUDS ]
Has he spoken English before ?
Never . Not once before .
Do they own a television ?
Yes , I believe so .
Okay , thank you .
[ BOY YELLING AND GROANING ]
[ AMORTH ] Ah ...
What are you drawing ?
A bird .
That 's good , kid .
[ YELLING CONTINUES ]
I have a very important job for you .
Do you know the Our Father ?
- Yes , Father . - Good .
[ THUDS CONTINUE ]
You can help your brother .
Repeat the Our Father , over and over .
Don 't get distracted . Relentless . Understood ?
Yes , Father .
Good .
Our Father , who art in heaven , hallowed be thy name ...
Bring me the pig .
- [ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ] - [ SCREAMING CONTINUES ]
[ GASPING AND GRUNTING ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] I am legion .
I am Satan .
I am foul-mouthed behemoth .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Difficult to believe .
You doubt me ?
If you are Satan , what is my name ?
Describe hell .
You will find out soon enough .
Are you avoiding my questions ?
You mock me ?
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ]
Answer me , Satan .
Why possess this boy ?
Why not someone more influential ?
I can possess anyone I choose .
Ah .
Could you possess Father Gianni ?
A bishop ?
- Anyone ! Anything ! - [ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] I do not believe you .
I don 't believe you could even possess this pig .
Can you do it ? You have the power .
Could you possess the pig ?
- Yes , I can . - Come on , Satan .
[ BOY ] Watch me !
[ AMORTH ] Possess the pig . Show me you are the Prince of Darkness .
[ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] Show to me your power .
Have you done it ?
[ IN ITALIAN ] Have you possessed him , Satan ?
[ SQUEALS ]
Have you possessed it , Satan ?
[ PIG SCREECHES ]
[ GASPING AND WHIMPERING ]
Be calm .
God blesses you .
[ IN ENGLISH ] You can sleep now , my son .
The demon has gone .
God is with you .
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ " SHE SELLS SANCTUARY " PLAYING ]
♪ Oh , the heads that turn ♪
♪ Make my back burn ♪
♪ And those heads that turn ♪
♪ Make my back , make my back burn ... ♪
[ SONG CONTINUES OVER HEADPHONES ]
Amy , we 're not in America anymore . You can 't dress like that .
Why ?
Because there 's gonna be construction workers everywhere .
[ SCOFFS ]
How you doing back there ?
♪ The world and the world ... ♪
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ CONSTRUCTION WORKERS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY ]
So we left everything for this ?
Amy , please . Don 't start .
- You know exactly what I 'm gonna say . - Yes , and I don 't wanna hear it .
What do you think ? Pretty cool , huh ?
Yeah , I know .
- [ SOFT CHATTERING IN ITALIAN ] - [ CHURCH BELLS RINGING ]
Cuckoo !
[ LAUGHING ]
- [ MIMICS ROAR ] - [ GIGGLING ]
Ah ... Gabriele .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Why do you think Saint Michael
didn 't kill Satan when he had the chance ?
[ IN ENGLISH ] That is a question of theology .
[ IN ENGLISH ] No shit .
Perhaps it was his mercy that stayed Saint Michael 's sword .
The only thing that arrests God 's love
is a person 's freedom to choose .
But God cannot be God unless he allows for this choice
even for the damned .
Saint Michael , he knows this .
We will all be judged .
We will all be judged
by how much we love .
[ LUMUMBA ] Hm .
Do not worry , Gabriele .
I will defend you .
Defend me ?
Mm .
My faith
does not require defense .
[ HAMMERING ]
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER ]
[ JULIA ] Oh-ho !
Wow .
- What do you think , guys ? - Cozy .
[ JULIA ] Oh , come on . Give it a chance . This is awesome .
- Señora Vasquez . - Carlos , hi !
So nice to put a face to the voice .
Um ...
Padre ... Father Esquibel ...
- Pleasure to meet you , Miss Vasquez . - Uh , Julia , please .
- Carlos was giving me a tour . - [ JULIA ] Oh , great .
I just wanted to stop by and welcome you and your family to the diocese .
- [ CARLOS ] I 'm sorry . - Oh , no , no , no , please . Go for it .
I 'm glad to see you made it safe .
[ AMY ] All right . Go find your room , twerp .
- [ SAW BUZZING , THEN METAL CLANKS ] - [ CONSTRUCTION WORKERS CHATTERING ]
Hey . Can I get one of those ?
[ IN ITALIAN ] Yes , of course .
[ ESQUIBEL ] This property has been in disrepair
- for as long as I can remember . - Thank you .
So it 's a wonderful thing you 're doing , restoring the abbey .
We are being very respectful of the existing architecture .
This has actually been in my husband 's family for generations ,
and we just inherited it .
Is Mr. Vasquez here or ... ?
Oh , uh , he passed , actually . About a year ago .
- I 'm sorry for your loss . - It 's okay .
If you need anything , please , hm , don 't hesitate .
Okay .
I will remember him in my prayers .
Oh , that 's very kind of you . Thank you . It was nice to meet you .
Okay , Carlos , talk to me . What 's up ? Where are we at ?
The basement excavation is very complicated .
[ JULIA ] More expensive , you mean ?
- [ CARLOS ] I 'm afraid so . - [ JULIA ] All right .
I 'll take another look at the plans .
If you could just show me what the basement looks like , maybe I can wire ...
Amy , get off of there before you break your neck .
Is that a cigarette ? Put that out right now , please .
- Fine . - No ! Oh , my God .
[ PLUMBING GROANING ]
[ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ MUSIC FADES ]
Cute .
Get out of my room .
[ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ]
[ " GONE DADDY GONE " PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES ]
♪ Beautiful girl , lovely dress ♪
♪ Where she is now , I can only guess ♪
♪ ' Cause it 's gone , daddy , gone The love is gone ♪
♪ Yeah , it 's gone , daddy , gone The love is gone ♪
♪ Yeah , it 's gone , daddy , gone ... ♪
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ MAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH ]
[ THUMPING ]
- [ MASONRY CLATTERS ] - [ GASPS ]
[ INDISTINCT DEMONIC WHISPERS ]
[ STONES CRACKLING AND CRUNCHING ]
[ " WE CARE A LOT " PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES ]
[ KNOCKING ON DOOR ]
Hey , have you seen your brother ?
Amy .
Look , I really can 't handle the silent treatment from both my kids .
- I know you don 't wanna be here . - Yeah , no shit .
Amy .
Please , I need your help .
This abbey is the only thing your dad left us .
We don 't have an income anymore .
Once we fix it up and sell it , we 'll go home . Okay ?
Maybe if you could just at least watch your brother .
Maybe try and get him to talk .
How ? He hasn 't spoken in almost a year .
Can you try for me ?
So you want me to be a mother for you ?
Please just keep an eye on your brother . Okay ?
[ MOUTHS ]
[ " WE CARE A LOT " CONTINUES ]
♪ Whoa , whoa ♪
♪ It 's a dirty job But someone 's gotta do it ♪
♪ We care a lot ♪
[ SONG ENDS ]
[ IN ITALIAN ] Hold this .
[ CHURCH BELLS RINGING ]
Father Amorth , caffe latte ?
[ IN ITALIAN ] At this time of the day ? Are you crazy ?
Double espresso , Sister .
Thank you .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Sugar ?
[ IN ITALIAN ] Sugar is the work of the devil . No , thank you .
Thank you very much .
Let 's get on with this already .
[ IN ENGLISH ] This is a formal hearing .
And as agreed , proceedings will be undertaken in English .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Ah . All right , let 's go .
On the night of June 4th , in the town of Tropea ,
you performed an exorcism
without the approval of the Reggio Calabria bishop .
[ IN ITALIAN ] It wasn 't a ...
In English , Father Amorth .
[ IN ENGLISH ] That was not an exorcism .
From Father Gianni 's description , what occurred in Reggio Calabria sounded
exactly like an exorcism , complete with animal sacrifice , no less .
The boy was maladjusted . A temporary mental illness .
I use primitive psychology .
The power of suggestion .
You addressed the subject as Satan , called for him to display his power .
- Do you deny this ? - No .
- That 's what I did . - And why would you do that ?
Exorcism is my job ,
but the vast majority of the cases to which I 'm assigned
do not require an exorcism .
They just need , uh , a little conversation ,
a little understanding ,
and sometimes ...
a little theater .
Cardinal Sullivan , in my observation ,
98 % of the cases that are assigned to Father Amorth
are then further recommended by him
to doctors and psychiatrists .
And the other 2 % ?
[ AMORTH ] Ah , the other 2 % .
This is something that has confounded all of science
and all of medicine for a very long time .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
I call it ...
evil .
[ LUMUMBA ] Your Eminence , with hundreds of successful exorcisms ,
- Father Amorth has been very effective ... - One moment , Bishop Lumumba .
You do raise an interesting point , Amorth .
You are not a doctor , but these practices of yours
could have damaging effects on these people .
You are right .
I am not a doctor .
I am not a psychologist .
But I am a theologian , I am a lawyer ,
I am a journalist , and I am a practical man .
I was also a partisan in the war , so I know a firing squad when I see one .
So , what is this about ?
The Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith
has recommended to this panel
that the position of chief exorcist be formally vacated .
So , what you are saying is that evil does not exist ?
The Church is under constant pressure to sharpen her relevance .
It 's time we move past these outdated beliefs .
Explain to me please , Your Eminence .
If evil does not exist ,
what , then , is the role of the Church ?
I think we all have to be careful of the Congregation of the Doctrine of the Faith .
Sounds to me like they want us all out of a job .
We have more questions for you , Father Amorth .
How is it that I am suddenly worthy
of the time and attention of all you powerful men ?
I ask you again ...
what is this about ?
Due process , Father .
So this is not about the dead girl , Rosaria Velendez ,
that I write about in La Madre di Dio magazine ?
What is your due diligence and process on this ?
- Please , cardinal . - I warn you ! I warn you ! Father Amorth ,
show respect to your superiors .
I do !
I am the chief exorcist of the Vatican .
My position was appointed by my bishop .
My diocese is Rome .
My local bishop is the pope .
If you have a problem with me ,
you talk to my boss . Okay ?
The pope is infirm .
Father Amorth , you have not been dismissed .
- Cuckoo . - Father Amorth !
- [ CRICKETS CHIRPING ] - [ FIRE CRACKLING ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ THUDDING ]
- [ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ] - [ WIND WHISTLING ]
[ CLANKING AND THUDDING ]
[ SHIVERS ]
[ CLOCK TICKING ]
Hello ?
Anyone there ?
- [ FLOORBOARDS CREAK ] - [ GASPS ]
[ HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING INDISTINCTLY OVER HEADPHONES ]
[ WALKMAN CLICKS , THEN MUSIC STOPS ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC INTENSIFIES ]
[ MAN IN SPANISH ] I can 't wait to finish this job .
This place freaks me out .
[ MASONRY CRUMBLING ]
[ INDISTINCT DEMONIC WHISPERS ]
What is it ?
I don 't know . Can 't see anything .
[ YELLS ]
- [ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ] - [ INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER ]
[ CARLOS ] They hit a gas deposit .
We can 't continue working here . I 'm pulling my team from this place .
[ IN SPANISH ] Come on , let 's go . Come on , everybody out .
[ JULIA ] Wait .
[ MAN ] Quick , quick .
[ HAUNTING MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ DEMONIC SNARL ]
[ AMY ] Henry ?
No . Henry !
Mom !
[ JULIA ] Oh , my God ! Henry ! What is happening ?
I don 't know , he was like this when I came in .
Henry ? Henry , it 's Mommy .
Talk to me .
- Henry . - Mommy .
He 's talking .
You 're all going to die .
[ JULIA ] Henry ! What are you doing ?
- Henry ! Henry ! - [ AMY ] Henry ! Henry !
[ MRI THUMPING ]
[ WOMAN ] X-rays , blood tests , even the spinal tap
and MRI show no results of ischemia or hematoma .
What does that mean ?
[ BOTH SPEAKING IN ITALIAN ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] All of his vitals and brain functions seem to be normal .
Wait , normal ? What do you mean ? He was convulsing .
[ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
Has he been through any trauma recently ?
[ SOBS ] Um ...
Yeah , uh , his dad died about a year ago .
[ BOTH SPEAK IN ITALIAN ]
[ WOMAN IN ENGLISH ] And how did he react ?
Uh ...
He hasn 't spoken since .
[ BOTH SPEAK IN ITALIAN ]
Wha ... Psychosis ?
No , that 's not possible . He 's just a little boy .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Ma 'am , there is nothing that we can do now .
- But he can recommend a good psychiatrist . - [ JULIA ] What is this ?
[ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
If your son continues trying to hurt himself ,
- you can administer him this sedative . - No .
- Mom . - I 'm so sorry .
Baby .
Oh , my God .
[ JULIA ] No , I don 't think you understand .
But this is an emergency , please .
No , I need to talk to someone at the consulate who can help me .
I need a specialist .
Okay .
Yes , please .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ BED CREAKS ]
[ JULIA ] Baby .
Hey .
My love , come here .
- [ CLATTERING ] - [ MICE SQUEAKING ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING AND HUMMING ]
Fuck this .
- Henry , no . - [ GROWLS ]
Henry , stop !
This baby 's hungry , you fat cow .
What ? What are you saying ? [ GASPS ]
You never breastfed me , Mommy .
- What ? - [ AMY ] What the fuck ?
- [ JULIA GROANS ] Ow ! - [ GROWLS ]
What the fuck is that ?
Bring me the priest .
- [ JULIA ] Can you help us ? - [ ESQUIBEL ] Yes .
I 'm here to help , Julia .
Okay .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING ]
- [ HENRY ROARS ] - [ ESQUIBEL GRUNTS ]
[ BOTH SCREAM ]
[ IN DEMONIC VOICE ] Wrong fucking priest !
[ ROARS ]
- [ IN ITALIAN ] Is that you , Gabriele ? - [ IN ITALIAN ] Yes , Holy Father .
They tell me you are sick .
Yes , they hope so .
They wish to see me weak .
But , no , they are .
[ SIGHS ]
- Help me . - Yes .
Perhaps we 've done our jobs too well .
Cardinal Sullivan and the younger generation ,
they don 't believe in the devil as we understand it .
It 's only an idea for them . For us , it is very real .
Two hundred fallen angels ,
expelled from heaven , driven beneath the soil where God is not welcomed .
It is not a fairytale .
Your search for truth is delightful , Gabriele ,
but pay attention to your desire to educate .
Pride manifests itself in different forms .
Pride ? Me ?
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] There 's a case that needs your attention .
A boy in Spain .
Something about it disturbs me greatly .
[ PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING ]
This boy 's possession is progressing very fast .
The incident took place in hallowed ground ,
San Sebastian Abbey in Castile .
This place has given the Church problems before .
I sense a great evil coming from there .
Something dark that only you can help solve .
I have requested the abbey 's records be brought to you in the library .
Look into it .
I will continue investigating while you 're on your journey .
[ IN ENGLISH ] " Our sins ...
will seek us out . "
[ POPE ] Gabriele .
Go to Spain , and help this child .
But be careful , this demon sounds dangerous .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ AMORTH ] Hello ?
[ MUSIC FADES ]
[ BIRDS SINGING AND INSECTS CHIRPING ]
[ DOOR CREAKS , THEN CLOSES ]
[ IN SPANISH ] Father .
Good morning . I 'm Father Tomás Esquibel .
- [ IN ITALIAN ] Spanish ? - Yes .
I am Father Amorth . Italian .
- [ IN ENGLISH ] Wait . Father Amorth ? - Yes .
Ah . I didn 't expect them to send you .
[ IN ENGLISH ] You know me ?
- Yes . I have read all the articles . - [ CHUCKLES ]
- And the books ? - No , no . No , not the books .
The books are good .
- I will read ... - Okay . I 'll just get my bag .
You , uh ... [ CLEARS THROAT ] Whiskey ?
No , no , no . Thank you .
[ CLEARS THROAT ] Yeah , this sore throat , the dust .
Julia , we have been extremely lucky . The Church sent someone .
An expert in these matters . Gabriele , please come in .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Good morning , good morning , good morning .
I am Father Amorth .
[ IN ENGLISH ] I have come from Roma .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Gabriele , how are you ?
I 'm sorry that you came all this way ,
but I don 't even know why the Church is interested in this .
I just want my son to be well .
[ AMORTH ] Yes , yes .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Tell me something , have the doctors given you any answers ?
Any comfort ?
If you would at least ...
just let me see your son .
I can give you my opinion and you can do with it what you will .
It 's worth a shot .
Okay . He 's upstairs .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Very nice , this .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Hello , my friend . [ CHUCKLES ]
Henry .
Are you awake ?
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ IN ITALIAN ] Our Father , who art in heaven ,
hallowed be thy name . Thy kingdom come , thy will be ...
[ IN ENGLISH DEMONIC VOICE ] Your prayers are worthless here .
[ GROWLING ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] Who are you ?
Your worst fear . I am your demise .
Why are you possessing this boy ?
Because it feels so good to ruin such innocent flesh .
But I prefer the challenge of an exorcist 's soul .
You only serve to diminish yourself .
Don 't lecture me , priest .
What is your purpose ?
I 'm here for you .
Then you must know my name .
I know your soul and every shameless sin .
Tell me one of my sins .
[ GROWLS ]
You cannot .
Because my sins have been absolved by the one true master ,
- the Lord Jesus Christ . - Do not speak of Him .
Are you afraid of Him ? Are you afraid of Jesus Christ ?
[ IN LATIN ] God is not here .
[ IN LATIN ] God is everywhere .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Whatever you do ...
you only do because God allows it .
Did he allow that ?
This is just the beginning .
You don 't know who you 're dealing with .
Then tell me . Tell me your name .
Unless you are too afraid .
I 'm not some stupid fuck you convince to get into a pig .
So you won 't tell me your name .
My name is blasphemy .
My name is nightmare .
Ah .
My nightmare ...
is France winning the World Cup .
You prideful fool .
You can 't hide behind your jokes forever ...
Gabriele .
I know your nightmares too .
[ DISTANT GUNFIRE ]
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ DEMON LAUGHS ]
[ IN GERMAN ] Show yourself , coward .
[ IN GERMAN ] Show yourself .
Coward .
Show yourself , coward .
[ LAUGHS ]
[ RETCHING ]
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ GROWLS ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] Beware , your sins will seek you out .
I 'll be waiting for you , Gabe .
Did you mention my name to anyone in this house ?
Maybe , I 'm not sure .
This demon , it says things that it could not know .
So it 's real ?
What do you know about demons ?
Only the basics , that they are fallen angels .
One serves the other in a hierarchy .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Yes .
[ IN ENGLISH ] The higher the demon , the more access it can have .
So why is it possessing the boy ?
This is a very good question . I 'm going to talk to the mother .
I need to work out why this demon has chosen Henry .
What I am about to say may be difficult . Confronting .
Your son is under the influence of a very powerful demon .
Removing the boy from this place could be fatal .
I say to you now ...
the only way your son comes back to you is through faith .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
Mrs. Vasquez , did anything happen to Henry ?
He was in the car accident that killed his father .
He saw his father impaled .
[ CAR HORN BLARING ]
That memory , that 's his demon .
I give you my word ,
I will not walk away from you , or your son .
Trauma such as you describe can be a gateway for the devil .
Suffering can make a soul desperate for connection .
It can make the innocent more vulnerable .
You must have loved your husband very much .
You have no idea .
He was your soul connection , sì ?
He was everything .
And you have two beautiful children .
A mother 's love is the closest thing we know to God 's love .
Tell me , Julia .
Have you ever believed ?
Uh , when I was a little girl ...
I used to think that my guardian angel walked me to school .
You should pray to that guardian angel .
[ " I 'M STRANDED " PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES ]
♪ I 'm stranded on my own ♪
[ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ]
♪ Stranded far from home ... ♪
- [ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ] - [ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ]
Henry ?
[ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ]
[ SNORING ]
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
Amy .
[ GROWLS ]
I 'm in hell .
[ AMY WHIMPERS ]
[ YELLS ]
[ GASPING ]
[ TELEPHONE RINGING ]
[ MAN ] Amy , honey , it 's Dad . You have to listen , okay ?
Daddy ?
[ DEMONIC VOICE ] You 're all going to die .
[ SCREAMS ]
Mom ! Mom !
Mom , it was Daddy . It was Dad .
I heard Dad 's voice . I heard his voice on the phone .
- He said that we 're all gonna die . - What ?
- He said that we were all gonna die . - Oh , my God .
[ AMY SOBBING ]
Shh .
What do we do ?
Coffee .
The demons , they grow more strongly in the night .
I 'm going to need my energy . But you should try to get some rest .
[ AMORTH IN LATIN ] And may the souls of all the faithful departed ,
through the mercy of God , rest in peace .
- Amen . - [ IN ENGLISH ] How long will this take ?
[ IN ENGLISH ] That is hard to say .
Hours .
Days , maybe .
This demon is very strong .
The boy won 't last long .
What we need to do is to find out its name in order to exorcize it .
That is the only way we can save the boy .
How do we do that ?
With prayer .
Constant prayer .
The demons , they are self-preserving .
They do not understand suffering .
Eventually , he will give himself up
because he cannot stand the pain of the prayer .
You understand me ?
- Yes . - Good . Good .
- Now , you must confess your sins . - Now ?
The demon can smell your sins if they are not absolved .
Come . [ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
[ IN ENGLISH ] We begin .
Forgive me , Father ...
for I have sinned .
It has been , uh ...
- eight months since my last confession ... - Padre , no .
Did you just say eight months since your last confession ?
- Yes . - I ...
Okay , we just have to get this done .
- You are a man of God , simple enough , sì ? - Yes .
And you are very , very sorry for all of your sins .
- Yes . - Okay .
May almighty God have mercy on you ,
and having forgiven your sins , lead you to eternal peace . Amen .
What rites of the exorcism do you know ?
- None . - None ?
It has never come up .
What prayer do you know that you could say over and over , even under pressure ?
The Hail Mary .
[ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
But if it is under pressure , I would prefer to say it in Spanish .
[ IN ENGLISH ] That 's fine .
Your job is to pray .
Do not engage with the demon .
Do not respond to anything it says or does .
Your job is to be implacabile .
Relentless . Okay ?
Good boy .
- You know any jokes ? - Eh ... no .
You should learn some . The devil does not like jokes .
[ AMORTH CHUCKLES ]
Bring the books .
[ AMORTH IN ITALIAN ] The scent of heaven .
[ DEMON ] I see you 've brought your friend .
He looks a little scared , Gabe .
Mind if I call you Gabe , Gabe ?
Readying for battle ?
You ran out on me last time , like the coward you are , soldier boy .
Not very becoming of the chief exorcist .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Who do you want to be vanquished by today , Jesus or His Mother ?
Fuck the Holy Mother .
Are we going to talk all night , or do you want to battle ?
Know what I 'm going to do to you , Gabriele ?
I 'm going to fuck you .
You 'll sense yourself coming .
And you 'll hate yourself for the release you feel when I fuck you .
And now we pray .
[ GROWLS ]
I command you , unclean spirit , whoever you are ,
along with all of your minions now attacking the servant of God , Henry ,
by the mysteries of the incarnation ...
- Fuck you and your incarnations . - ... passion , resurrection
and ascension of our Lord Jesus Christ , by the descent of the Holy Spirit ,
by the coming of our Lord for judgment , to tell me by some sign
your name and the day and hour of your departure .
Tomás , pray . Pray .
I command you , moreover , to obey me to the letter ,
I who am a minister of God , despite my unworthiness ...
[ CRICKETS CHIRPING AND WIND WHISTLING ]
Rosaria ?
- Your sins will seek you out . - [ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
My sins have been forgiven .
But you can 't forgive yourself , can you , Father ?
Not for me , the girl you let die .
Why did you do nothing ?
Why didn 't you believe me ?
Now I am in hell .
Deceiver .
Her soul rests in peace .
[ IN DEMONIC VOICE ] My soul rots in hell !
[ MUSIC INTENSIFIES ]
How touching .
Is that all you got ?
And how about you , panty sniffer ?
[ INHALES ]
You didn 't tell him , did you ?
About your little whore ?
Your little sweet treat , Adella .
After you stood before your congregation like you 're better than them ,
when you 're fucking their daughters .
Maybe you aren 't so sorry about that sin .
- Hm ? - Shut up .
Tomás . Tomás .
Do not speak to it .
- Pray . - Run away .
You don 't want to be here , Tomás .
You 'd rather be fucking that little whore .
Tomás ! Tomás ! No ! No , no ! That 's what it wants !
Ah !
[ GROWLING ]
You 've been played , Amorth .
You took the bait .
And I 'll destroy you .
Your holy Church will crumble from the inside .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ DOOR CREAKS OPEN ]
[ MAN IN ITALIAN ] The abbey 's records , Your Holiness .
She was the love of my life .
A promise was made .
[ POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYING ]
She wanted me to ...
leave the priesthood for her ...
but I had ...
no intention of doing that .
So I just told her what she wanted .
My love for God ...
it outweighed my love for her .
Are you sorry for your sins ?
Yes .
May almighty God show you mercy .
And having forgiven your sins , may he lead you to eternal life .
Amen .
Who is ...
Rosaria ?
She is a girl that I should 've helped .
The demon is using her memory to deceive me .
How does it know these things ?
It can sense our guilt ,
and it uses it against us as a distraction .
That boy , he does not have long before he expires .
We need to find out the name of this demon .
Knowing its name , it weakens them .
I didn 't mean to hurt him .
I understand .
See here .
I have marked this page for you .
Learn that .
But it is in Latin .
Close enough to Spanish .
Prayer has more power in Latin .
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
" You have taken the bait . "
- What ? - What it said to me .
" You have taken the bait , Amorth . "
This is not about the boy .
It has a bigger plan .
I need to check something I saw in the garden .
Go . Take this . Be outside his door . He is still in danger .
We must protect him at all cost . Do whatever you have to .
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
The seal of the Vatican .
[ POPE ] This place has given the Church problems before .
[ PRAYING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ IN LATIN ] God , by your name ...
save me .
- [ HENRY IN NORMAL VOICE ] Help me . - [ THUMPING ]
Henry ?
- [ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ] - [ GASPS ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING ]
Henry ?
[ ESQUIBEL YELLS ]
[ IN DEMONIC VOICE ] No one 's getting out of here alive !
[ LAUGHS ] No one .
[ THUNDER RUMBLING AND RAIN PATTERING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ RHYTHMIC KNOCKING ]
- [ KNOCKING ] - [ WHIMPERING ]
- [ KNOCKING CONTINUES ] - [ SCREAMS ]
- [ DEMONIC GROWLING ] - [ THUDS ]
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ KNOCKING CONTINUES ]
[ MUFFLED SCREAMING ]
Let 's see what secrets you are hiding .
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
- What happened ? - [ JULIA SCREAMING ]
[ AMY SCREAMS ]
Go !
- [ INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING ] - [ MUFFLED SCREAMS ]
[ GASPING ]
[ AMY SCREAMING ]
[ DEMON GROWLS ]
[ AMY SCREAMS ] Help me !
Amorth !
[ AMY ] Help me !
Help !
[ JULIA ] Amy !
[ IN LATIN ] In the name of Christ , let her go .
In the name of Christ , let her go .
- [ AMY SCREAMS ] - [ JULIA ] Amy !
[ AMY ] Help !
[ AMORTH ] In the name of Christ , let her go .
It 's me . It 's me .
Oh , my God . Oh , Amy .
[ AMORTH ] In the name of Christ , go away , Satan , go away !
[ DEMON GROWLS ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
It 's one of her nails .
[ AMORTH IN ENGLISH ] Tomás , take them to the chapel .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC CONTINUES ]
Everything is redacted .
" Our sins will seek us out . "
- Are you okay ? - Yes .
You don 't get to stay handsome in this business for too long .
Please . Hm ? Don 't .
I once have a demon try to put a crucifix into my eyeball .
You 're always talking and talking . Enough .
- Please . - [ SHUSHING ]
They 're sleeping .
No more stories .
Did you consider why the demon does this ?
To scare us , hm ?
For what benefit ?
Chaos .
Distraction .
The devil is the great deceiver .
He can make you see things from your past .
Apparitions , memories , always trying to deceive us .
So we never know what he 's thinking , what he 's planning .
If you do not believe me ...
just ask my friend .
Come , I 'll show you what I found .
Amorth !
[ AMORTH ] I noticed this when I first arrived .
What is this ?
You recognize this ?
Yes , it 's the seal of the Spanish Inquisition .
Sì . The darkest time in the history of the Church .
And they are ... ?
The victims . The ones who would not convert .
There is something underneath this place .
Something is hidden here . Come .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
Hold this .
Two crossed keys .
Do you recognize this ?
- It 's the Vatican seal . - [ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
- Is it gas ? - [ IN ENGLISH ] A little gas .
A little sulfur . A little death .
So no smoking , huh ? [ CHUCKLES ] Stand back .
- [ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ] - [ GROWLS ]
It 's a door . Push with me .
Okay .
Catacomb .
This is how they would bury the dead .
I understand the Vatican sealing this place off .
But why would they leave someone ?
[ AMORTH ] The ring of the cardinal protector .
He was the final hope , the last protector .
It looks like he 's a prisoner , but he 's not .
The cage is for his own safety .
They do this when an exorcism fails . To protect against a demon 's escape ,
to trap something they need to remain hidden .
Tomás , see if you can open this gate .
[ IN LATIN ] " Your cardinal protector writes to inform you of our worst fears .
A great evil has taken hold of San Sebastian Abbey .
It must be buried here forever . "
It 's locked .
Then our friend here ...
must have a key .
Where did you hide your key ?
In the stomach .
Forgive me .
- [ GAS HISSES ] - [ GAGS , THEN COUGHS ]
Try this .
Go .
" All attempts at exorcism have failed .
Satan owns this ground now .
I have never seen a demon this powerful before . "
[ GROANING ]
[ SPEAKING IN ITALIAN ]
Gabriele .
[ SIRENS WAILING ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
It worked .
Ah .
Thank you , my friend .
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
- [ THUMPING ] - [ GIRL SCREAMING , THEN LAUGHING ]
Amy ?
[ ESQUIBEL COUGHS ]
The gases and the sulfur , it 's getting stronger .
We are getting closer to hell .
Cardinal Sullivan , is he all right ?
He collapsed .
[ LUMUMBA ] Holy Father .
[ EKG BEEPING ]
[ IN ITALIAN ] You are just agitated .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Tell him .
[ IN ENGLISH ] Tell who ?
Gabriele .
Gabriele ?
- [ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ] - Amorth ?
- [ EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY ] - [ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
Amorth ?
What trouble has he got us into this time ?
[ AMORTH ] The Friar De Ojada .
One of the greatest exorcists of all time .
[ ESQUIBEL ] The seal of the Spanish Inquisition .
His journal .
" Today ...
I was summoned to the town of Segovia . "
A possessed monk .
" In the year of our Lord 1475 .
While questioning the demon possessing the monk ,
he answered me from the mouth of another .
And then a third . "
Multiple possessions .
It 's a powerful demon .
[ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
[ JULIA ] Amy ?
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ DEMONIC GROWLING ]
[ AMY LAUGHS ]
" The exorcist becomes possessed himself . "
Friar De Ojada ?
You know he is the man who convinced Queen Isabella
of the need for an Inquisition ?
So that means from the time he is possessed in 1475 ,
everything that happens after this ...
is the work of the devil .
Centuries of persecution and torture , the worst abuses of the Inquisition ,
all started by the friar and done in the name of God
by the devil .
The Vatican must have known this .
The Church covered it up .
And they buried the truth here .
" Your sins will seek you out . "
The construction work must have freed the demon .
[ JULIA ] Amy ?
[ AMY LAUGHING ]
Amy ?
Henry .
- It 's okay , Mommy . - It 's okay , Mommy .
- Henry 's okay . - Henry 's okay .
Oh , that 's great .
Listen , Amy , why don 't you come downstairs with me ?
- I 'm sorry , Mom . - I 'm sorry , Mom .
- I don 't know what got into me . - I don 't know what got into me .
Well , that 's okay .
That 's okay . I just need your sister for a minute . Amy ?
- Can you forgive me , Mom ? - Can you forgive me , Mom ?
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
" The great dragon was hurled down .
Hurled into the earth , where he was bound . "
" And his angels with him . " Revelations .
Two hundred rogue angels buried into the earth .
This abbey is one of those godforsaken places .
This demon , he was trying to find them .
To raise an army and destroy the Church .
Amy , come here .
- What 's in your hand , Mommy ? - What 's in your hand , Mommy ?
Amy , come here , right now .
- [ GROWLS ] - [ SCREAMS ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ GROWLS ]
Look .
[ DEMON ] Watch me , Mommy .
Watch me .
[ AMORTH ] His name ...
the king of hell ...
Asmodeus .
[ ROARS ]
[ EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY ]
Quickly !
[ JULIA ] Amy , use the sedative .
[ GROWLS ]
Tie his arms .
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
We have his name .
" Bring me the priest . "
What did you say ?
Those were the first words the demon said . " Bring me the priest . "
It didn 't mean me .
It wants you .
This demon feeds on exorcists .
He had a plan once .
To lure the friar here ,
hide amongst the righteous and commit heinous acts
in the name of God .
He wants to do the same thing again .
Using me to infiltrate the Church .
What greater victory for the devil ...
than to claim the soul of the pope 's exorcist ?
Maybe . But we know his name now .
So we have what we need to beat it
and to save the child .
The only thing that can defeat us is ourselves .
He will use your sins against you .
I need to make confession .
- To me ? - You are a priest , are you not ?
Forgive me , Father , for I have sinned .
Trust in the Lord .
I want to talk to you ...
about things I have confessed before ...
but they still burden me .
In 1942 ...
during the war , I joined the Resistance .
I became a partisan and I fought against the fascists .
[ POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYING ]
So many of my friends would die to German bullets .
Why them ...
and not me ?
Their dead bodies would talk to me in my dreams .
To die in a war is heroic .
To survive a war ...
complex .
And then I begin to see ...
that my life had been spared .
It was my responsibility to give it purpose .
And in my case , that meant to serve God .
In all of my years , I have tried to embrace what is said in Matthew .
" What you do for the least among you , you do for me . "
But when it mattered ...
I failed .
I did not help her ,
I did not believe her .
I did not listen .
- Rosaria ? - [ SPEAKS IN ITALIAN ]
Rosaria .
At night , the devil fucks me .
[ IN ENGLISH ] What does this devil look like ?
You .
She was not possessed .
She was mentally disturbed .
So I let someone else handle her case .
Again ...
my pride .
I was an exorcist .
The mentally disturbed , it 's not my job .
Do you believe me now ?
But that all changed because of her .
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ]
To hear
after her death
the rumors of the sexual abuse , the coverup
within the walls of the Vatican City .
That innocent girl .
I did not help her when she needed me .
Her soul
is my burden .
And this demon , he knows that .
I know you ...
as a humble man of God , Father Amorth .
It 's time to lay down that burden .
Forgive me , Father .
I absolve you of your sins
in the name of the Father , of the Son , and of the Holy Spirit .
Amen .
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ CLOCK TICKING ]
I give you the miraculous medal .
Holy fire insurance .
Very powerful .
To defeat the king of hell ...
we require the armor of God .
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ DEMON SHRIEKS ]
Remember , the demon will use your sins against you .
Do not believe everything you see or hear .
We have work to do .
We must save this child .
[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ GROWLS ]
All done confessing ?
Father .
Did he bare his soul to you , Tomás ?
Like your little whore bared her breasts ?
[ GROWLS ]
Ignore it .
Pray for Henry .
No amount of prayers can save Henry .
Let me in , Gabriele .
You know what I want .
[ AMORTH ] Our Father , who art in heaven ...
- In heaven , hallowed be thy name . - ... hallowed be thy name .
Thy kingdom come , thy ...
Was there really any point confessing to your God , Gabe ?
- Give us this day our ... - Shouldn 't you be confessing to her ?
You are not there .
You are only in my mind .
[ GROWLS ]
I burn in hell because of you !
You are not there .
You are only in my mind .
- Father . - [ ASMODEUS ] Join us in hell , Gabe .
Take me in .
[ ASMODEUS AS ADELLA ] Don 't you want me , Tomás ?
Tell me to get on my knees and say my prayers .
Fuck me , Tomás .
- Deceiver . - Fuck me , Tomás !
- Deceiver ! - Fuck me , priest .
- Oh , God . - [ AMORTH ] Tomás , focus on the prayer !
Asmodeus !
[ GROWLS ]
Asmodeus , king of Gehemma , this is the cross of the Lord !
Release this child and flee from the light of God !
See thee beneath God !
Never . Get out .
- Get out of my house . - This is the house of God !
Not without my son !
[ ASMODEUS ] Your son is gone .
His soul burns and rots in hell .
- Admit to thy name , Asmodeus . - Never !
And bow to the power of God almighty .
- [ ASMODEUS ] Take me in , Gabe . - [ ALL ] Oh , Mary ...
[ YELLS ]
- ... Lord is with thee . Blessed art thou ... - And of the angels ...
[ ASMODEUS ] I am king .
You 're under my dominion .
- We humbly beseech you ... - And here you will remain damned forever !
... now and at the hour of our death .
... to crush Satan 's skull .
I am Asmodeus , king of hell .
And I command you !
We beseech thee to send thy holy angels , that under thy command and by thy power ,
they may pursue the evil spirits , encounter them on every side ,
resist their bold attacks ,
and drive them hence into the abyss of woe !
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] Mommy ?
Mom , help me .
Speak to him , Julia . Speak to him .
A mother 's love never fails .
[ JULIA ] Henry . Henry , I love you .
- Call to him . - Henry , come back to me .
Henry , please talk to me .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING ]
Mommy , they 're hurting me .
Oh , God .
Henry , we need your help .
You must resist .
I can 't .
You must resist !
Mom ?
Henry .
What 's happening ?
[ JULIA GASPS ]
Oh , my God .
Holy shit .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Almighty God .
It 's in them both .
[ GROWLS ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
Amy .
- Give me what I want ! - No !
[ ASMODEUS ] Surrender yourself to me .
[ ROARS ]
Julia !
[ IN DEMONIC VOICE ] I told you , bitch .
You 're all gonna die !
- Amy , please . - Amy 's gone .
Julia , resist !
Don 't lose faith !
Give me back my children !
Your children are gone !
Please .
Amy , please .
I love you .
[ LAUGHS ]
[ ROARS ]
[ AMORTH ] It 's me you want . Let the children go .
They all suffer because of you .
Say the words , piggy .
Be the martyr you dreamed of being .
Be my piggy .
[ AMORTH ] Take me .
[ ROARS ]
[ INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
Mom ?
No , Gabriele !
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ ESQUIBEL ] Father .
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
[ IN NORMAL VOICE ] Mommy ?
What have you done ?
- Take the cross from my hand . - Okay .
- Take it . - Okay .
Oh , my God . Oh , my God .
Oh , my God . Henry , you came back to me .
- You 're safe now . - Take it !
Get them out of here . Go !
[ ESQUIBEL ] Hey . Hey .
Julia , we have to go !
- Put your arms around me . - Let 's go .
Come on , run . Amy , come on .
[ ASMODEUS ] Your soul is mine .
Sullivan .
Sullivan !
[ SULLIVAN WHIMPERS ]
[ YELLS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ GROANING ]
I knew you would sacrifice yourself to save those children ,
and now you are mine .
[ INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
Come on . Hurry .
The boy , he 's safe now . Just get away from here .
- Go . - Thank you , Father .
[ ASMODEUS ] I need my pig , Gabe .
[ YELLS ]
You will not take me .
You will not take me !
[ ASMODEUS LAUGHS ] You prideful fool .
The friar said the exact same thing .
[ AMORTH ] Forgive me , Lord .
[ ASMODEUS LAUGHING ]
Not yet !
I need my pig to get me inside the Vatican , Gabe .
[ GROWLING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ SNARLS ]
Gabriele !
Damn us both ...
to hell .
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
Gabriele !
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ IN DEMONIC VOICE ] You 're too late , Tomás .
He 's gone , your friend . Gone .
So ...
run along .
[ LAUGHS ] It would be my great pleasure
to excoriate your soul and eviscerate your memory .
Gabriele , listen to me . Fight it .
It is just in your head .
We can only be defeated by ourselves .
He is not here !
The little piggy is slopping at hell 's trough , where he belongs .
I know you 're here , Gabriele . Pray with me .
God is not here !
God is always in our hearts .
Focus on the prayer .
" Where two of you gather ...
in My name , there am I. "
Lord , have mercy .
Say it ! Lord , have mercy !
God is with you , Gabriele . Find him !
[ AMORTH ] Finish it , Tomás .
Finish it !
[ IN LATIN ] God , by your name , save me .
[ AMORTH IN LATIN ] Judge me in thy strength .
O God , hear my prayer .
Listen to the words of my mouth .
Behold , God is my helper .
[ ASMODEUS ] Give up . He is mine .
[ IN ENGLISH ] I adjure you in the name of the spotless lamb .
The word made flesh commands you .
Asmodeus !
Jesus of Nazareth commands you !
And now , I adjure you in His name !
[ ROARS ]
Lord , heed my prayer !
- Say it ! - No !
- Gabriele . - We 're not done yet .
You 're coming to hell , priests .
I will take you both .
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ]
Adella .
[ IN DEMONIC VOICE ] Your sins will seek ...
Seek you out !
[ AMORTH ] Tomás , use the medal !
Lord , grant me the power !
- [ MUSIC INTENSIFIES ] - [ YELLING ]
Gabriele !
Asmodeus . In the name of the Holy Mother .
See thee beneath God .
See thee beneath God !
Tomás ! Pray the final rites .
In the name of the Father , and of the Son , and of the Holy Spirit ...
see thee beneath God !
[ ROARS ]
[ COUGHS , THEN GROANS ]
Gabriele , are you okay ?
Not so bad .
[ COUGHING ]
- Tomás . - What ?
You look like shit .
[ AMORTH CHUCKLES ]
Bless you , Tomás .
You learned the Latin .
[ LAUGHS ]
Yes , it 's similar to the Spanish .
[ LAUGHS ] Very similar to the Spanish .
Look .
Perfetto .
You know , the God , he works in very mysterious ways .
For you .
[ HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING ]
Yes , he does .
[ HOPEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES ]
Cuckoo .
Is that you , Gabriele ?
[ AMORTH IN ITALIAN ] Yes , Your Holiness .
[ IN ENGLISH ] And I have brought Padre Esquibel to meet you .
You look well , Your Holiness .
Thanks to you both . I 'm glad to see you .
You had me worried this time .
Sounded dangerous .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Yeah , not too bad .
Sometimes you fly a little too close to the sun .
[ IN ENGLISH ] It has not killed me yet .
The Church will not forget what you have done .
You struck a mighty blow for our side .
Saint Michael would be proud .
And this is why God put you here , Gabriele .
[ IN ITALIAN ] Thank you very much , Your Holiness .
And God has made a good choice in you too , Father Esquibel .
Thank you , Holy Father .
The congregation has requested a full report on Spain .
[ IN ENGLISH ] A full report .
So Cardinal Sullivan can tell me again that evil only exists in my imagination ?
You haven 't heard ?
Cardinal Sullivan has taken a sabbatical in the Isle of Guam .
I shall pray for Guam .
And who has , uh , filled his shoes ?
I have found someone far more trustworthy .
I will leave you in his good hands .
See thee beneath God .
- See thee beneath God . - See thee beneath God .
[ CHURCH BELLS RINGING ]
[ LUMUMBA ] Welcome to the holiest of holies .
Twelve centuries of treasures .
Letters from saints and apostles .
Books of wisdom and piety .
Revelations of the spirit .
The entire canon of Christian thought .
The Vatican has purchased the abbey from the Vasquez family
and reconsecrated the soil .
The family has safely relocated back to the U.S. ,
where the boy made a full recovery .
Hm .
The friar 's diary is proving very useful , despite his abhorrence .
Asmodeus has been defeated , but there are many more to be found .
Soon we will know all of the other 199 sites on earth
where God is not welcome .
Gabriele , will you take on this task ?
[ PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING ]
This would be more than a lifetime 's work for one priest .
But two priests ...
What do you think , Tomás ? Can you see this now as a calling ?
And that we must serve God the way he wants us to serve him ?
Let 's go to work .
Let 's go to hell .
[ MUSIC TURNS DRAMATIC ]
[ HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ MUSIC INTENSIFIES ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING ]